<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mind the gap blog: Insights, ideas, and inspiration for the tech-savvy and curious.</title>
    <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mind the gap blog: Insights, ideas, and inspiration for the tech-savvy and curious.</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://mindthegapblog.com/mindthegap-tmp-picture.png</url>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/mindthegap-tmp-picture.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2022-2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 19:20:29 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mindthegapblog.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dying isn&#39;t as sad as Not living.</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/we-all-have-a-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 19:20:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/we-all-have-a-mission/</guid>
      <description>Leaving this here for posterity: &amp;ldquo;Dying isn&amp;rsquo;t as sad as Not living.&amp;rdquo; —Valentin Viennot, 2023
I know; death is a sad and probably not the most exciting topic for a post. But you needed to read it. In fact, this post is more about life than death. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a wake-up call, an invitation even.
I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer that our life choices are investments that shape the value and meaning we extract from life itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All we do is invest.</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/all-we-do-is-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 10:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/all-we-do-is-investment/</guid>
      <description>All we are doing is investment. Taking the bus to meet a friend? That&amp;rsquo;s an investment. Quitting your job to work at another company? That&amp;rsquo;s investing. Skipping the gym? Bad investment, but still one. Going to bed early? Probably a good investment. So let me give you my best investment advice: spend your time wisely. Imagine you are a millionaire and you are placing your entire fortune into 24 chunks of money every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Open Market series.</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/open-market-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 15:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/open-market-series/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the playground of my thoughts, a maze of ideas that&amp;rsquo;s been simmering in my mind, only now finding their way to the surface, and to you. This upcoming series of posts truly fits with the vision of the Mind the gap blog. We&amp;rsquo;ll be diving into a topic close to my heart, a complex puzzle made up of many pieces and deep reflections I&amp;rsquo;ve been nurturing for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to colorize black &amp; white pictures.</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/colorize-black-white-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 11:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/colorize-black-white-pictures/</guid>
      <description>If you’re looking to bring a stack of old family photos back to life, check out Ubuntu’s demo on how to use OpenVINO on Ubuntu containers to colorize monochrome pictures. This magical use of containers, neural networks, and Kubernetes is packed with helpful resources and a fun way to dive into deep learning!
A version of Part 1 and Part 2 of this article was first published on Ubuntu’s blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordle-ing our way: CNN experiment to solve wordle grids.</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/wordle-solver-ai-cnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/wordle-solver-ai-cnn/</guid>
      <description>Are you a fan of Wordle, the addictive word puzzle game? Have you ever wondered what is the best word to play first? In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore the use of Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) to solve Wordle grids with a success rate of over 80%.
I should clarify that I&amp;rsquo;m not a data scientist – while I have a passion for machine learning and have completed a few courses on the subject, I am not an AI expert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the mind the gap blog!</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/welcome-mindthegap-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 23:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/welcome-mindthegap-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I&amp;rsquo;m Valentin, a passionate inventor using technology to make the world a better place. I am on a mission to increase both individual and collective intelligence, and to inspire and challenge you to think critically. This blog will mix thoughts, experiments, and ideas on a various topics, including tech, design, and society.
I grew up with a natural curiosity and a desire to solve problems with my ideas and inventions.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
