<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Mind the gap blog: Insights, ideas, and inspiration for the tech-savvy and curious.</title>
    <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Mind the gap blog: Insights, ideas, and inspiration for the tech-savvy and curious.</description>
    <image>
      <title>Mind the gap blog: Insights, ideas, and inspiration for the tech-savvy and curious.</title>
      <url>https://mindthegapblog.com/mindthegap-tmp-picture.png</url>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/mindthegap-tmp-picture.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022-2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 20:00:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mindthegapblog.com/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The future of work.</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/future-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 20:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/future-of-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We work because we are humans. Looking back at humanity&amp;rsquo;s history, the evolution of our modes of subsistence shows how central the modes of production and the organisation of human labor are in providing for our material needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans work in order to give meaning to their lives. We work in order to consciously, intentionally shape our surroundings. We work as a socially organised way to expand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We work in order to create value.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principle of equitable empowerment</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:51:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Knowledge must be freely accessible to all, providing the foundation for informed autonomy and enabling the collective intelligence necessary to address systemic issues and develop collective ambition. Communities must have the freedom to self-organise, and societal structures should facilitate serendipitous innovation and resilience, ensuring that every individual has the same opportunity to contribute to and benefit from the collective effort to solve our biggest problems and achieve their own mission. Structures should be here to empower, not to disable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common tragedies: Funding open source vs Saving the planet</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/saving-the-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 10:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/saving-the-planet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post —&lt;a href=&#34;https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/why-open-source/&#34;&gt;Why Open Source isn&amp;rsquo;t Profitable&lt;/a&gt;—, I explain the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/why-open-source/#the-curse-of-competition&#34;&gt;Curse of Competition&lt;/a&gt; as a sort of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/1724745&#34;&gt;Tragedy of the Commons&lt;/a&gt;: because open-source intellectual property is free to access, all economic agents will exploit it without giving back (a.k.a. as the &lt;em&gt;free riders&lt;/em&gt; issue). If the resource is finite, then its value will tragically be destroyed by this unrestrained consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the same analysis, we can explain how and why our current dominant economic system will eventually consume all of the available natural resources and destroy all living species. That is, unless proper regulations were to be globally adopted (&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalrepository.unm.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1848&amp;context=nrj&#34;&gt;Governing the Commons: The Evolution of Institutions for Collective Action&lt;/a&gt;, Elinor Ostrom, 1992).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Open Source isn&#39;t Profitable</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/why-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/why-open-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a Capitalist economy, Open Source has no (direct) value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-is-not-profitable&#34;&gt;Open source is not profitable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a few definitions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the price is the exchange value of a good or a service in a socio-economic context,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the production cost is what it costs to build a good or deliver a service,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added value is the price minus the production cost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open-source software delivers an &lt;em&gt;added value&lt;/em&gt; close to or below zero. As the &lt;em&gt;price&lt;/em&gt; for using it is zero so is the &lt;em&gt;added value&lt;/em&gt;, no matter the &lt;em&gt;production cost&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dying isn&#39;t as sad as Not living.</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/we-all-have-a-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 19:20:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/we-all-have-a-mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving this here for posterity:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dying isn&amp;rsquo;t as sad as Not living.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
—Valentin Viennot, 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know; death is a sad and probably not the most exciting topic for a post. But you needed to read it. In fact, this post is more about life than death. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a wake-up call, an invitation even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer that &lt;a href=&#34;../all-we-do-is-investment/&#34;&gt;our life choices are investments&lt;/a&gt; that shape the value and meaning we extract from life itself. Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re all going to die; get over it. But surely, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave this world with a life unlived. There&amp;rsquo;s no perfect time to start investing it wisely and bravely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All we do is invest.</title>
      <link>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/all-we-do-is-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 10:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindthegapblog.com/posts/all-we-do-is-investment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All we are doing is investment. Taking the bus to meet a friend? That&amp;rsquo;s an investment. Quitting your job to work at another company? That&amp;rsquo;s investing. Skipping the gym? Bad investment, but still one. Going to bed early? Probably a good investment. So let me give you my best investment advice: spend your time wisely. Imagine you are a millionaire and you are placing your entire fortune into 24 chunks of money every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
